他们说自己是Genii人.
They call themselves the Genii.
他们很单纯,但也是出色的农夫和商人.
They are a simple people,
but good farmers and fair traders.
他们看上去十分友好.
They look friendly enough.
年纪最长的是 Tyrus.
我和他也打过好几次交道.
The eldest one is called Tyrus.
I've traded with him on many occasions.
我正带他们进来.
所有设备进入静止状态.
I'm bringing them in.
All operations to silent mode.
你知道的,如果人们只会
You know, if people could just learn to keep their
躲在地下的秘密基地里面...
secret underground hatches locked...
所以这所有的农业有关的东西只是掩饰.
So the whole farmer thing is just a front.
下一次的大淘汰可能是在几十年之后.
The next culling was supposed to be decades away.
我们希望大家联合起来对付幽灵.
We're looking for allies against the Wraith.
我们希望未来五年内可以测试成功我们的原子武器.
We had hoped to test our first
atomic weapon five years from now.
我们有这么多时间么, Sheppard?
Do we have that much time, Sheppard?
没有.
No.
和幽灵飞船的电脑系统的连接对你有没有帮助?
How does getting access
to a Wraith ship's computer help you?
根据这个界面装置,我们可以找到所有幽灵飞船的位置.
With this interface device, we can learn
the locations of all the Wraith ships.
所以你现在知道往哪运炸弹了.
So you know where to deliver your new bombs.
幽灵一定不知道我们来过这里.
The Wraith must not know we were ever here.
-帮帮我.
- 别管他了.
- Help me.
- I said leave him.
-求你!
- 安静!
- please!
- Be silent!
我爸爸呐?
Where is my father?
他没有逃出来.
He did not survive.
把他留在那里等于你亲手杀了他.
By leaving him to die, you may just
as well have killed him yourself.
你不想和 Genii的任何一个人成为敌人.
You do not want to make an enemy of the Genii.
我很久没回去了.
I haven't been to the mainland in a while.
大家都怎么样了?
How's everybody settling in?
Halling觉得第一批作物的收成会不错.
Halling believes the first crops will have a good yield.
大家还是很想家?
Everybody still miss home?
大家仍然在谈论回去的事情,尽管我跟他们说幽灵
There is still talk of returning,
even though I've told them the Wraith have
为了报复我们的反抗,把Athos烧死了.
scorched Athos bare in revenge for our resistance.
嗯,这里会开始像家的.
Well, maybe in time, this place will start
to begin to feel like home.
你看见了么?
Do you see that?
这不会是风暴.
It can't be a storm.
它正席卷而来.
It stretches across the whole horizon.
我从没见过这么高的东西.
I've never something like that from so high.
在这个高度我见过很多东西,除此之外.
I've seen a lot of things from this altitude,
but nothing like that.
Atlantis基地, 我是探险者一号.
Atlantis base, this is Jumper one.
我们准备调转方向,研究一个风暴.
We're going to change our heading
to investigate a storm.
少校, 我是Weir.
Major, this is Weir.
我们没有信号了,你断线了.
We didn't copy that.
You're breaking up.
我说这里有...
I said there's a...
它正向着...
And it's headed right...
小型天气预报.
Little weather forecasting.
他说"天气预报"?
Did he just say "weather forecasting?"
是不是从上面看所有的风暴都这样?
Do all storms look like this from above?
不.
No.
这至少覆盖了星球20% 的地区.
This must cover 20% of the planet.
它是不是正向着大陆?
Is it headed towards the mainland?
它的轨迹显示它正向着基地.
It's tracking right toward the settlement.
然后呐?
And after that?
正对Atlantis.
Straight to Atlantis.
星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯
第一季第10集 飓风
Season 1 : Episode 10
The Storm
这个星球基本上和地球大小一样.
This planet is basically the same size as Earth.
但是,地球上的飓风从来没有如此强烈
Now, hurricanes on earth never
get as big as this bad boy
因为他们一到达海滨,就会小很多...
because once they hit the shore,
the brakes get put on...
但是这里没有这么大块的陆地让它减速, 所以
But without as much land mass
to slow it down here, it's just
它只会越来越迅猛.
gaining momentum.
他们两个都是,是的.
Both of them are, yes.
两个?
Both of them?
我们只看到了一个.
We saw only one.
看起来就像是一个.
It only looked like one.
根据远古时代的记载,
Now, according to the ancient database,
每20到30年,
海洋会变得非季节性的温暖.
every 20 or 30 years,
the sea gets unseasonably warm.
而现在,但气温过于稳定时,
Now, that, for reasons too boring to get into,
飓风发生的几率就很大.
means that hurricanes are much more likely to occur.
就像El Nino,海洋...
Like El Nino, the ocean is...
就像我说的,没有温差变化.
Like I said, too boring to go into.
重点.
Focus.
看,基本上就像这样一个状况
Look, basically if you have a situation
这里将要很多飓风发生,
where there are a bunch of hurricanes out there,
两个飓风相遇的几率就变大了.
the likelihood of two colliding is greatly increased.
这就是现在的情况.
That's what's happening.
与其说是相撞,不如说是合并.
It's more like a merger than a collision.
它们将彼此的力量综合.
They are intersecting and combining their power.
然后呐?
And?
向着我们笔直而来.
It's headed right towards us.
你刚才说古代,这样的飓风每20年到30年发生一次.
You just said the Ancients experienced
these storms every 20 to 30 years.
Atlantis必须设置一些预警措施.
Atlantis must have some precautions put in place.
以前,这里有防御系统的保护,
In the past, the ancients have
been protected by the shield,
要不就是在深深的海底,根本侵袭不到.
or submerged deep enough in the water not be affected.
好,除去这些呐.
Okay, strike those options.
还有什么方法?
What else have we got?
没有.
Nothing.
这的确是个威胁,这么强烈的风会带来很大的破坏.
If it's a real threat,
the high winds alone will wreak havoc.
来吧,伙计们,这座城市已经存在很久了.
Come on, guys, I mean, this city's
been around for a long time.
飓风的侵袭是不可避免的.
A storm surge is inevitable.
别在说什么在它袭击我们之前转移,
Not to mention the fact that by moving
over a land mass just before hitting us,
飓风和电击的可能性都很大.
the likelihood of tornadoes and
electrical activity is greatly increased.
这就是Atlantis.
This is Atlantis.
我的意思是我们可以控制...
I mean, we've got to be able to handle that...
是么?
Right?
不.
No.
为什么不?
Why not?
因为建造这座城市的人知道,他们有力量
The people who built this city
knew they had a force field
可以控制自然的一切,
capable of holding back anything mother nature,
或者,这样,幽灵才会受挫.
or, for that matter, the Wraith could throw at them.
除去这层保护,
Atlantis显然是很不堪一击的.
Without that protection,
Atlantis is remarkably fragile.
根据我们的保守估计,也会造成大面积的结构损伤.
Even our conservative calculations
project widespread structural damage.
洪水会将整个城市淹没.
Flooding could sink the city entirely.
像Atlantis如此巨大的东西沉没会怎样?
How could something as big as Atlantis just sink?
我相信Titanic上的乘客们业在问自己同样的问题.
I'm sure the passengers on the Titanic
were asking themselves the same question.
是的,还是不要了.
Yes, well, let's not.
那么,如果我和Teyla没有发现这个的话要怎么办...
So, what you're saying is if Teyla and
I hadn't discovered this...
那我们的麻烦就更大了.
We would be in even bigger trouble.
好吧,那现在怎么办?
All right, what's the plan?
根据我的计算,飓风还有12个小时就会侵袭我们,所以,嗯...
By my calculations, we have just under 12 hours
until the storm hits, so, uh...
让我们来好好计划一下.
We plan to have a plan... Yeah.
那么.
By then.
我们需要好好计划一下如何撤退,
We need to start investigating evacuation plans,
包括大陆的和海外的.
both on the mainland, and off-world somewhere.
你知道的,McKay可能会有些什么主意.
You know McKay will come up with something.
他一直认为自己是个英雄.
He's just setting himself up to be a hero.
是的,可能Rodney 才是,
但是Zelenka博士, 他真的很关心.
Yeah, well, maybe Rodney is,
but Dr. Zelenka, he seemed genuinely concerned.
所以我的计划就是
So my orders are to come up with
找到一个友好的星球,可以让我们避一个晚上.
a friendly planet that wouldn't mind
putting us up for the night.
正确.
Exactly.
加上Ford, 看看你们能弄出点什么.
Take Ford, see what you can work out.
老实说我不是干这个的正确人选.
I don't really have the right boots for this.
我是过来这边给小孩子们接种疫苗的.
I was just meant to come out here
and inoculate some wee babies.
在飓风到来之前,我们需要尽可能多的帮助.
We need all the hands we can spare before it comes.
这场飓风不仅会毁了我们的庄稼,
This storm could not only destroy our crops,
我们的居所可能也会被刮走.
our settlement could be washed away.
如果只有很少的人留下...
If just a few of us were to remain...
庄稼可以再种,房子可以再造...
Crops can be replaced and homes rebuilt...
但是人不能再生.
People can't.
这就是为什么我们现在一定要竭尽所能.
Which is why we must do what we can now.
正确.
Right.
所有的Atlantis人?
The entire population of Atlantis?
基本上是吧.
At most, yes.
只是一两天.
Only for a day or two.
至少大多数.
At most.
很高兴可以用我们的粮食跟你们交换...
We are happy to trade with you
for a share of our crops...
但是这个.
But this.
我知道这个要求过分了点...但是,求您了.
I know it's a lot to ask, but... I'm asking.
那么你怎么回报我们?
What do you offer in return?
我们欠您一次人情.
I guess we'd owe you one.
一个什么?
One what?
一个要求.
A favor.
看,我们现在有麻烦.
Look, we're in trouble.
如果你是我们的朋友,那么请帮助我们.
If you're our friend, you'll help.
如果不是,那么现在告诉我,我会去找其他人.
If not, tell me now so I can ask somebody else.
但是还有谁会接受这么多人?
But who else would take in so many?
我希望得到一些有价值的回报.
I want something of value in return.
哦,当然,不是么?
Oh, you do, do you?
你知道的,我们可以去找没有人住的星球.
You know, we can go find any uninhabited planet.
它们都有不适合居住的理由,少校,
They're usually uninhabited for good reason, Major,
这点你和我一样清楚,
否则现在你不会在这里.
and you know that as well as I do,
or you would not be here.
当然,你也可以找到其他的星球接受你们...
Still, I'm sure you could find
another world to take you in...
但是你们没有时间了.
You're just so short on time.
如果有天你碰到困难
One day you're going to run across a problem
你也会需要我们的帮助.
and you're going to need our help.
不是么,中尉?
Isn't that right, Lieutenant?
是的,长官.
Yes, sir.
我们需要很多飞船和武器.
We've got lots of ships
and weapons we can... help with.
你在说我们要不是朋友要不...
You're telling me we can either be your friends or...
我比较喜欢朋友.
I much prefer friends.
这个对我比较有价值.
That is of value to me.
一晚上,两个最好的.
One night, two tops.
我们会自己带毯子的.
We'll bring our own blankets.
很好.
Very well.
你们可以运送你们的人来了.
You may send your people.
不会忘记的.
This won't be forgotten.
我们马上回去告诉所有人这个好消息.
We'll go back and tell everybody the good news.
要是有什么新消息我们会马上告诉你的.
I'll send word once we know more.
我等着.
I look forward to it.
不,不,不,不,不,
No, no, no, no, no,
- 我已经想到了.
- 他可能有点想法.
- I've already thought of that.
- He may be onto something.
我想到了,他不是...
I've already thought of it! It doesn't...
是的,这个naquadah能量发生器
Yes, the naquadah generators
可以给城市里选定的区域提供能量,
could be used to power select sections of the city,
但是，当你为了保护他们,而将他们从需要被保护的区域中减去的话.
but when you subtract the areas that need
to be secured just to protect themselves,
剩下的能量,什么也保护不了
it doesn't leave much power to shield anything else
这座城市会因为潮汐的力量而分开.
and the city breaks apart
because of the tidal stresses.
我们可以将他们重新组合,
把他们连得更紧.
Well, we could relocate some of them,
put them closer together.
没错,如果我们有奇妙的可以让减慢时间速度的工具.
You're right.
If only we had a magical tool to slow down time.
我傻傻的把那个留在地球上了,你带了你的么?
I foolishly left mine on earth.
Did you bring yours?
你知道...
You know...
你这个样子让人不舒服, McKay.
You're not pleasant when you're like this, McKay.
- 我一直是这样的.
- 没错.
- I'm always like this.
- My point exactly.
Smeadon和Manarians同意接受我们了.
Well, I've got a green light
from Smeadon and the Manarians.
但是我们要是一直不走,就不知道他们会怎样了.
I'm not sure how pleased he'll be
if we get stuck there, though.
不会发生这种事情的,不是么?
That's not going to happen, right?
当然不会.
我们还可以去其他星球.
Of course it's not.
We can always gate off to another planet.
令人安慰. 谢谢.
Comforting. Thank you.
你确定大陆上没有其他地方可去了么?
Are we sure there's no part
of the mainland we could go to?
在飓风来的路上我们探索了每个角落.
Everywhere that we have explored
is in the path of the storm.
尽管如此,我们的人已经开始撤退了.
My people are evacuating even now.
还是Ford对.
Still, Ford's right.
大陆只有北美这么大.
The mainland is the size of North America.
你的意思是整块大陆都会遭到飓风的侵袭?
You're telling me
the entire continent is going to get hit?
我轻易不欠Smeadon一个人情.
I'd rather not owe Smeadon any favors.
如果我们失去了Atlantis,我们就只能待在大陆上,无法进入星际之门.
If we lose Atlantis, we'll be stuck
on the mainland without any access to the Stargate.
McKay会想到办法的.
McKay will come up with something.
我会努力想的,但我也不是超人啊.
I will try, but despite what
you all may think, I am not Superman.
还有人也这么认为么?
Was anyone seriously thinking that?
不,长官.
No, sir.
不.
Never.
好的.
Fine.
我的观点是飓风会侵袭大陆70%的区域
Atlantis也不安全.
My point is the storm will affect over 70%
of the mainland, and Atlantis isn't safe either.
如果你不想有人伤亡,那就得把他们弄出去.
If you want everyone to live, you gate them off-world.
2号中转站, 准备接受发送.
Relay station two, prepare receive transmission.
R.S.2 准备发送. 完毕.
R.S.2 awaiting transmission. Over.
我需要你给Genii的Cowen传个消息.
I need you to relay a message to Cowen, of the Genii.
跟他说我们有个交易.
Tell him we have something to trade.
应该更快.
This could be going faster.
我们的人是猎人, 中尉.
Our people are hunters, Lieutenant.
很多人从很远的地方赶来.
Many are returning from great distances.
还有人不愿意离开.
Others do not want to leave the settlement.
他们知道这会有多严重.
They know how serious this is.
就算是我也很难相信这个飓风会有多可怕
Even I would have a hard time believing
in the strength of this coming storm
如果不是在太空中亲眼见到.
if I did not see it from space.
好吧,想办法让他们快点.
Yeah, well, do what you can to speed things up.
在Czech Republic
我们就不用对付飓风了.
In the Czech Republic
we don't have to deal with hurricanes.
在加拿大我们也不会常遇上这个...
We don't get that many in Canada either...
曾经有个叫做"Hazel."的
Once something called "Hazel."
Hazel?
- 40年前.
- 挺有趣的.
- Forty years ago.
- That's interesting.
也不是啦.
Not really.
不,不是这样的.
No, not really.
我有一次差点被闪电击中.
I was once almost struck by lightning.
闪电?
Lightning?
我们无法得到防御系统的一个阻碍是什么?
What is the one thing keeping us from having a shield?
- 是...
- 能量.
- That would...
- Power.
那么一个从地底升起mega飓风拥有最多的是什么?
And what does a mega-storm from hell have lots of?
能量.
Power.
以怎样的形式?
In the form of?
你想造个大风车.
You want to build a windmill.
电能.
Electricity.
Atlantis是可以经受电击的.
Atlantis is designed to withstand
substantial lightning strikes.
城市到处都有避雷针.
There are lightning rods all over the city.
这些针将电引入四个主要的地下站.
Those rods are channeled
into four main grounding stations.
是的,反过来,这四个地下站将电导入大海
Yes, in turn, those grounding stations
discharge electricity back into the ocean,
使得Atlantis免于遭受由于闪电带来的强力电击.
keeping Atlantis safe from massive
electric shocks due to lightning strikes.
现在,大部分的走廊都铺设了超导材料,
Now, many of the hallways are lined with a
superconductive material that allows a safe,
使得城内的能量可以转化为安全的低压.
low voltage transfer of power throughout the city.
- 这当然就意味着...
- 我明白了,我明白了.
- Which, of course means...
- I'm getting there, I'm getting there.
如果没有地下站
Let's say the grounding stations weren't around,
每次闪电电击城市的时候,
every time lightning struck the city,
这些走廊就会充满电.
those halls would become supercharged.
等等,你想...
So wait, you want...
如果我们可以停止地下站...
If we could disable the grounding stations...
如果可以.
Which we think we can.
每次闪电电击城市的时候,
Every time lightning struck the city,
Atlantis会承受一个瞬间的巨大能量.
Atlantis would experience
a momentary massive power surge.
- 现在能量...
- 如果正确导入...
- Now, that energy...
- If it's channeled correctly, though...
是的,它们当然会被正确导入,
Yes, of course if channeled correctly,
就可以启动防御系统了.
could conceivably be used to
charge up the shield generator.
现在,飓风越强烈,能量就会越多
Now, the more severe the storm,
the more energy is produced
防御系统就可以运行更长时间.
and the longer we can keep the shield running.
哦,这真是个天才的计划.
Yeah, it's an ingenious plan, really.
我不得不同意.
I'm compelled to agree.
唯一的缺点是如果我们没有办法储存所有的能量.
The only downside is we have no way of
storing all that energy.
啊,一旦飓风停止,闪电停止...
Ah, once the storm stops and
the lightning stops striking...
我们就无法再运行防御系统.
Yeah, we have no way of charging up the generator.
那我们就退回到以前.
Then we're back to square one.
那这个城市就可以逃过一截了么?
So the city would survive?
90%的机会.
I'd give us better than 90%.
70.
80% 的机会.
80% chance.
好吧,我们还是会继续转移.
Okay, so we should still evacuate.
的的,但不是因为Zelemka的悲观.
Yes, but not just because of Zelemka's pessimism.
Zelenka.
如果这个计划成功,那么这个城市就会变得高度依赖电力.
If the plan works, the city will become
highly charged with electricity.
一旦闪电开始,唯一安全的地方是控制室.
The only safe place to be once the lightning
begins to strike is in the control room.
我们需要把所有人都转移出去在飓风到来之前
We need to evacuate everyone
off-world until the storm passes
同时用尽可能少的人执行计划.
and execute the plan with the smallest team possible.
好的.
Okay, good.
开始吧.
Get on it.
好的.
Right.
地下站.
The grounding stations.
不,我想我们应该先去能量发送站.
No, I think we should go to
the power distribution centers first.
啊,不错.
Ah, good point, good call.
我在超越自己.
I'm getting ahead of myself.
是,好的,所有...
Yeah, okay, so...
Kolya长官...
Commander Kolya...
Cowen首领说要马上见你.
Chief Cowen needs to see you immediately.
我在训练的时候不想被打扰.
I am not to be disturbed while training.
他说马上,长官.
He said "immediately", Sir.
还没有转过来么?
Still haven't turned up yet?
恐怕是的.
I'm afraid not.
他们在打猎.
They are on a hunting mission.
没人能告诉他们撤退的消息.
No one has been able to get
them word about the evacuation.
多少?
How many again?
3个.
Three.
2个男孩和一个年轻女人.
Two boys and a young woman.
为什么我们不驾驶探险号去找他们?
Why don't we just take our Jumper and go find them?
他们在很深的森林里,就算可以找到他们,
They are hunting in dense vegetation.
Even if we were able to locate them,
我们也无法着陆.
we would be unable to land.
探险者3号已经装满准备走了,你或许应该--
Jumper three is loaded and ready to go.
Maybe you should just--
直接走.
Just go.
我继续等他们.
I will stay behind and give the hunters more time.
我和你一起.
I'll stay with you.
好吧,我明白了.
Okay, I get the point.
我们等.
We'll wait.
- 他们还没准备好.
- 当然没有.
- They're not ready.
- Of course they are.
你命令我训练一队男人,
You commissioned me to train a group of men who,
在最困难的一天保护这些东西
on their most treacherous day,
guarded this facility
或者执行一些侦察的任务.
or performed some sort of reconnaissance mission.
他们现在还不行.
They are not yet a strike force.
这个机会很难得.
This is the rarest of opportunities.
之后的一个小时内,Atlantis里只会有不足10个的人,而且大部分都是科学家.
Within the next hour, there will be less than
10 people on Atlantis, most of them only scientists.
你肯定可以完成任务.
Now, surely you can accomplish our goals
并在暴风到来之前顺利撤退.
and get out before the storm hits.
如果一切顺利...
If all goes well...
但是我们在训练的时候不会假设一切都进行的很顺利.
But we don't train assuming all will go well.
我们不可以错失这个机会.
We cannot afford to pass up this opportunity.
如果你需要我的意见.
You wanted my opinion.
我已经说了.
I gave it to you.
而且我认为这个意见...
And I value that opinion...
但是Atlantis人手中拥有大量的资源,这些资源对于我们对抗幽灵非常重要 .
But the Atlantians are in possession of materials
that are vital to our goal of defeating the Wraith.
我们需要它们.
We need them.
我需要它们.
I need them.
让你的人做好准备吧.
Ready your strike force.
就是他们.
That's everybody.
还有4个半小时,飓风就要来了.
We've got just over four and a half hours
until the storm hits.
我们去实验室.
Let's get down to the labs.
探险者2号的人一到,立刻疏散他们.
Evacuate the people on in-bound
Jumper two as soon as they come in.
遵命,长官.
Yes, sir.
现在,我总算是习惯它的味道了.
I'm finally at the point where
I don't mind the taste of it.
我一直吃这个.
I was raised on this brew.
我已经不记得其他东西的味道了.
It burned away whatever taste sense I had.
所以...
So...
你觉得你会教我们的农夫一点什么么?
You think you can teach our farmers a thing or two?
是的是的,这就是我说的,是的.
Yes, yes, that's what I was saying, yes.
大多数人认为中庄稼就是要有好的种子
Most people think that farming is planting good seed
在肥沃的土地上.
in well-tilled soil, which it is.
的确如此,但是还需要其他的东西.
It is, but there's also more.
这些东西...就在这儿.
And that knowledge is... Here.
那么你想用这些奇妙的知识
And you want to trade these marvelous skills
来交换我的一块土地么.
in an exchange for a piece of my land.
没错.
I do.
我觉得我还要需要更多东西.
I think I'll need something more.
你是谁?
Who are you?
告诉我密码.
Tell me the sequence of numbers to enter in this device.
我不能说.
I can't tell you that.
为了这个去死不值得.
It isn't worth dying for.
你不会明白的.
You don't understand.
需要我的手纹才能开.
It's my hand that you need to put in the code.
这就是它的原理.
That's how it works.
Atlantis 的防御系统就会减弱?
And the shield of the Atlantis Stargate will be lowered?
是的.
Yes, yes.
这是什么?
What is this?
他们是谁?
Who are they?
带他进去.
Bring him to the Gate.
他们是朋友, Doran.
They are friends, Doran.
让他把密码输进去.
Make sure he will enter the code.
他会的.
He will.
照他说的做,我们就会看到那块大陆了.
Do as they say, and we'll see about that piece of land.
你帮了Genii一个大忙,我们会奖励你的.
You have done a great service
for the Genii and will be rewarded.
现在,这儿有几十个,
甚至可能上百个避雷针
Now, there are dozens,
possibly hundreds of lightning rods
分布在城市的四周.
placed strategically around the city.
等等.
Wait a sec.
- 怎么了?
- 为什么?
- What?
- Why?
什么为什么?
Why what?
为什么城市的周围会有上百只避雷针?
Why are there hundreds of lightning rods
placed around the city?
防御系统不是就可以对抗闪电了么?
Wouldn't the shield protect against lightning?
是的,是的,但是一直启动防御系统只有一个结果...
Yes, yes, it would, but running the shield
all the time is only good for one thing...
把能量耗尽.
Draining power.
正确.
Right.
你应该很清楚时间的重要性,对吧?
You're aware that there is a time element
to what we're doing here, right?
是的,我注意到了.
Yes, it's been brought to my attention.
就像我说的...
Like I was saying...
有避雷针,
There are lightning rods,
城市四周,到处都是.
a lot of them, placed all over the city.
这样的话,他们所捕获的所有能量
Now, as it stands right now,
all the energy they capture
全部会被传送进四个地下站.
is routed into four main grounding stations.
接着,地下站会将所有的能量传送进我们脚下的大海.
In turn, these stations ground
all that energy into the ocean below us.
所以,我们不要让电量传送到地下...
So instead of sending electricity to ground...
我们用他来启动我们的防御系统.
We use it to power the shield.
怎么做?
How?
将它们导入Atlantis的走廊
By directing it right down the corridors of Atlantis
然后进入能量发生器.
and into the shield generators.
能做到么?
The city can handle that?
是的,理论上可以.
Yes, theoretically.
就像,恐龙理论上也可以变成鸟???
Like, dinosaurs turned into birds "theoretically,"
或者就像相对论,所谓的理论上.
or theory of relativity "theoretically?".
什么?
What?
呃....差不多吧
Elizabeth...
Uh... somewhere in between.
你负责2号地下站,
You take grounding station two,
我负责一号.
I'll take grounding station one.
少校,你负责3号和4号.
Major, you take stations three and four.
什么,等等,3号和4号在哪里?
Whoa, wait a sec, where are stations three and four?
这里和这儿.
Here and here.
那我们在...
And we are...
是的,这里.
Here, yes.
我们必须要快,这样 我才能开始设置主要程序,
I need to get done quickly so
I can start working on the sub-routines,
Elizabeth 抱怨她的膝盖...
and Elizabeth was complaining about her knee...
等等.
Whoa, wait a second.
这些东西是不是类似一个传送器?
Are these things even close to a transporter?
是的,Elizabeth的是这样的.
Uh, yes, Elizabeth's is.
那我的呢?
And mine?
这是个轻松的旅程.
It's a brisk walk away.
你说的轻松是指很远吧?
And by brisk you mean far?
我说的漫步是要用跑的.
And by walk I mean run.
好吧.
Okay.
你到达第一个站的时候跟我们联系.
You'll need to radio in
once you've gotten to your first station.
知道了,开始吧.
All right, let's do it.
快,行动!
Hurry! Move!
这边!
Come this way!
你还好么,还好么?
Are you okay? You okay?
他们来了.
Here they come.
好了,坐好,系好安全带.
Okay, just sit here.
Strap in as best you can.
这一路上会很颠簸.
It's going to be a real bumpy ride.
好吧,我们走吧.
All right, let's get out of here.
我不确定这是个好主意.
I'm not so certain that's such a good idea anymore.
什么?看外面.
What?
Look at it out there.
就算是Sheppard少校也搞不定 .
Even major Sheppard would have
a hard time flying through this.
我们准备好了.
We are ready.
我想我们还是等等好了.
I think it's best that we wait it out.
在这还挺安全的.
We're safe as long as we're in here.
我们有吃的,也有水.
We've got rations, and there's plenty of water.
是啊,特别是相对于外面来说.
Yeah, especially outside.
很好.
Very well.
希望你是对的,博士.
I hope you are right, Doctor.
如果你错了,我们就没有机会再选了.
We won't have a chance to change
our minds if you are wrong.
这挺舒服的.
It'll be cozy.
我到了!
I'm here!
我跟你说了到达第一个站的时候跟我联络, 少校.
I told you to contact me when you got
to the first one, Major.
我在第一个, Rodney.
I am at the first one, Rodney.
哦,抱歉,我刚搞定.
Oh, sorry, I'm already done mine.
哦,很好,.
Oh, great, good for you.
我也是.
Me too.
大家都好.
Good for everyone.
你现在在哪里?
Where are you now?
我在该死的地下站.
I'm at the damn grounding station.
不,不,不,不是说你.
No, no, no, no, not you.
我在传输器这里.
I'm in the transporter.
你在那里.
There you are.
我在这儿.
There I am.
很高兴大家都很顺利.
Glad everybody is having such a good time.
我现在该怎么做?
What do I do?
控制台上应该有一个按键台.
There should be a key pad right
on the console of the station.
看到了.
Got it.
输入 0-3-1-5-4-7在远古时代的替代语.
Punch in the ancient equivalent of 0-3-1-5-4-7.
就这样?
That do it?
是的.
Yep.
好了,搞定3个,还差一个.
Good, three down, one to go.
他们的密码好像都一样,
They all seem to have the same separation code,
呃,现在去最后一个,重复这个操作程序,
so, uh, get to the next one, repeat the procedure,
我们在控制室汇合.
we'll meet you in the control room.
Roger那是.
Roger that.
熏肉.
Bacon.
你想要带的是熏肉?
The one thing you wish you'd brought with you is bacon?
吃了这个,你就会觉得其他东西都很美味.
It's the food that makes other food worth eating.
你想把熏肉带着去另外一个星系?
You wish you brought bacon to another galaxy?
是的,你问我...
Yes, you asked me...
让其他的东西变得美味.
Off-world activation.
Weir博士说明天之前应该不会有人到.
Dr. Weir said no one should be
coming back until tomorrow.
有人袭击了Manara.
There's been an attack on Manara.
有伤员回来,减弱防御系统.
We have wounded incoming!
Lower the shield.
他们在用Athosian IDC.
They're broadcasting an Athosian IDC.
拜托,否则就迟了.
Please! Before it's too late.
我们正在减弱防御系统.
We are lowering the shield.
嗯,我们应该经过Weir博士的同意.
Whoa, we should get the okay from Dr. Weir.
他们被袭击了,减弱防御系统吧.
They're under attack.
Lower the shield.
Weir博士,好像 Manara受到了袭击.
Dr. Weir, there's been some sort of attack on Manara.
有一小队受了伤的athosian.
We have an athosian party incoming with wounded.
我们正在路上.
We're on our way.
出什么事情了?
What happened?
他们怎么到处都是!
真不敢相信他们没把我们都干掉.
They were everywhere!
I can't believe they didn't kill us all.
谁?
Who?
守住这个房间.
Secure the room.
只有把这些人制伏就可以了.
These men could have been overpowered.
我们需要和Atlantis人合作.
We need the Atlantians to be cooperative.
守住房间.
Secure the room.
把入口守好.
Cover the entrances.
看起来有伤员回来了.
Apparently there's wounded incoming.
没什么意义.
That doesn't make any sense.
你是说和幽灵有关?
They said it was Wraith-related?
一会我们自己去问他们.
等等.
We'll ask them ourselves in a second.
Hold on.
大厅怎么了?
What the hell is going on?
Elizabeth Weir博士?
Dr. Elizabeth Weir?
是的?
Yes?
那么你一定是McKay博士了.
And you must be Dr. McKay.
没错.
That is him.
Sheppard少校呢?
Where is major Sheppard?
Sheppard在哪里.
I would like to know the whereabouts of major Sheppard.
你好像对我们很了解.
You seem to know a lot about us.
你是谁?
Who are you?
他们是Genii.
They're Genii.
你只需要知道一件事, Weir博士.
There's only one thing you need to know, Dr. Weir.
现在...,我们控制了 Atlantis.
As of right now... We are in control of Atlantis.
呼叫探险者2号, 我是Sheppard. 快回答我.
Puddle Jumper two, this is Sheppard. Come in.
探险者2号,收到么?
Jumper two, do you copy?
我是 Ford, 长官.
This is Ford, sir.
我们决定待在探险者2号里面,等风暴过了再回去.
We decided to wait out the storm in the Jumper.
你们还在大陆?
You're still on the mainland?
是的,长官.
Yes, sir.
嗯,我们这里出事了.
Well, we've got a situation, here.
据我所知,
一小队Genii武装力量闯了进来 .
From what I can ascertain,
a small Genii strike force has gated in.
Genii?
The Genii?
那些想让我们给他们原子弹的人?
The folks who wanted us to build them an A bomb?
是的,就是他们.
Yeah, that's them.
他们抓了Weir 和McKay 当人质.
They've got Weir and McKay hostage.
他们控制了入口.
They've also got control of the gate room.
没听清, 长官, 你刚才说人质?
You're breaking up, sir, did you say hostage?
没错.
Affirmative.
我们马上回去.
We're on our way.
你以为自己在干什么?
What do you think you're doing?
你听到他说的啦.
You heard him.
看看外面.
Take a look outside, hotshot.
我们无法飞回去的.
We're not flying through this.
McKay 和 Weir被抓了,博士.
McKay and Weir were taken hostage, Doc.
我没准备在这儿傻等着什么都不做.
I'm not just going to sit here and do nothing.
我们都不是专业的飞行员.
Neither one of us are real pilots.
如果说在一个小时前飞回去是个坏主意,那么现在就是一个愚蠢的决定.
If it was a bad idea an hour ago,
it's an idiotic one now.
我们会把握机会.
We'll going to have to take our chances.
Beckett 博士说得对,中尉.
Dr. Beckett is right, Lieutenant.
我们现在对Sheppard少校毫无帮助 .
We are of no use to major Sheppard dead.
少校,我是Teyla.
Major, this is Teyla.
外面的风暴太猛了.
The hurricane is in full force outside.
我们可以试着起飞,
We could attempt to fly through it,
但是我很怀疑我们能飞回去,
but it is doubtful that we would
make it back to Atlantis,
我们还有3个年轻的乘客.
and we have three young passengers.
真糟糕.
That's bad news.
我很抱歉.
I am sorry.
我也是.
So am I.
你们就待在那里等风暴停止.
You stay put until it passes over.
- 长官, 我...
- 没问题的,中尉.
- Sir, I...
- It's okay, Lieutenant.
尽快赶回来就好.
Just get your ass back here as soon as you can.
我还可以撑一会.
I could use a little backup.
祝您好运,长官.
Good luck, sir.
你是谁?
Who are you?
Acastus Kolya司令,Genii人.
Commander Acastus Kolya, of the Genii.
Atlantis 真是特别...
This Atlantis is extraordinary...
跟我想象的完全不一样.
More than I ever imagined.
你把我们的其他人怎样了?
What have you done with the rest of my people?
我很肯定他们甚至不知道我们的到来.
I'm quite sure they have no idea we're even here.
那么他们是安全的?
Then they're safe?
是的.
Yes.
你们是如何通过防御系统的?
How were you able to bypass the shield?
多亏了那些陈年酿造的酒和这些没脑子的家伙.
With the time-tested combination
of strong drink and weak minds.
我以为我们大家是盟友.
There was a time when our two peoples
considered becoming allies.
为什么这么做?
Why are you doing this?
你们拥有我们非常需要的东西.
You are in possession of supplies we vitally need.
把这些给我们,我们就走,这很简单.
Hand them over, without difficulty,
and we leave peacefully.
否则呢?
Or?
我们都是聪明人, Weir博士.
We're both intelligent people, Dr. Weir.
我想没有必要向你们再次展示我的决心?
I'm sure there's no need for me to demonstrate
once again the strength of my resolve?
你们要什么?
Which supplies did you have in mind?
你们所有的 C-4炸药,
All of your stores of the C-4 explosive,
你们所有的药品,
all of your medical supplies,
还有从我们那里偷走的幽灵的数据装置...
the Wraith data device you stole from my people...
还有一艘你们的飞船.
And one of your ships.
就这些?
Is that all?
不.
No.
Sheppard少校呢?
Where is major Sheppard?
他在大陆.
He's on the mainland.
你要的那些东西并不容易准备.
What you're asking for isn't that easy.
我们正准备转换大量的能量为即将到来的风暴做准备.
We've had to divert a lot of power
in order to prepare for the storm.
军工厂的安全门已经关了,所以我们不能...
The armory safety doors have shut, which means we can't...
我们很明白,我知道你在撒谎.
just so we're clear, I know you're lying.
Elizabeth, 给他们.
Elizabeth, just give him what he needs.
如果他要C-4, 药品,
If he needs the C-4, the medical supplies,
还有幽灵数据装置,那么给他们.
and the Wraith data device, then just give it to him.
不值得为了这些东西去死.
None of that is worth dying for.
离开控制台.
Step away from the console.
我明白了,我明白了.
I was leaning.
I was just leaning.
你们的要求很不合理.
Your request is unreasonable.
你们不可能需要我们所有的 C-4和药品.
You can't possibly need all our C-4,
or all our medical supplies.
你现在没有资格和我讨价还价.
You're in no position to tell me what
is reasonable and what is not.
我们怎么知道如果你得到你要的东西之后不会杀了我们?
How do we know that you won't kill us
once we give you what you need?
你不知道.
You don't.
告诉我的士兵们哪里可以找到我们要的东西.
Please show my men where they can find
what they're looking for.
你在这里干什么?
What are you doing here?
在我看来,我手上有人质.
From my understanding, I'm being held hostage.
我是说在这里,在Atlantis.
I mean here, in Atlantis.
你们为什么留下?
Why did some of you stay behind?
收拾残局
做些扫尾工作.
Tie up some loose ends.
比如说?
Like what?
你知道的,确保每个人都离开了.
You know.
Make sure everyone got out okay.
这些事情让其他人去做不就可以了么?
Isn't that the work of someone less important?
你不这么认为么?
You'd think so, wouldn't you?
你有什么计划吧?
You have a plan, don't you?
是的,我有很多计划.
Yeah, I've got lots of plans, about lots of things.
我对于你要拯救这个城市的计划比较敢兴趣.
I'm interested in the plan you have to save the city.
我没说过要拯救什么.
I never said anything about saving anything.
是还有没有.
Not yet.
Teyla Emmagan在哪里?
Where is Teyla Emmagan?
你认识 Teyla?
You know Teyla?
她在城里么?
Is she here, in the city?
不,不在.
No, she isn't.
你一定是Sora.
You must be Sora.
我看过Genii代表团的报告 .
I read the Genii mission report.
对于你父亲的事情我很抱歉.
I'm sorry about your father.
我会为他报仇的.
He will be avenged.
Teyla没有杀他.
Teyla didn't kill him.
不.
No.
- 她把他留在那里等死.
- 她没有其他选择了...
- She left him to die.
- She had no choice...
你说完了么?
Are you finished?
我们从幽灵的飞船上载下来的数据都在这个装置里面.
All of the information we downloaded
from the Wraith ship is still on this device.
他们对你做了什么?
What did they do to you?
我不想说,但是...
I tried to keep my mouth shut.
I tried, it's just I couldn't...
这是什么意思?
What is the meaning of this?
我真的不知道.
I honestly have no idea.
这是个通信器.
It's a radio.
箭头指向通话按钮.
The arrow points to the talk button.
我是Kolya司令.
This is commander Kolya.
Kolya...
这个名字很难念.
That's a hard name to pronounce.
是名么?
Is that a first name?
我是John Sheppard少校,
My name is major John Sheppard,
我把所有的C-4都藏起拉了,你们永远,我再说一次,永远也找不到.
and I have hidden the C-4
where you will never,I repeat, never, find it.
除非我知道人质被安全释放
When I get confirmation that the prisoners
have been safely released
并且离开了 Atlantis,
我会告诉你们在哪里.
and allowed to gate off Atlantis,
I will help you find it.
他很好.
He is good.
没错.
Yes, he is.
我会照他说的做.
I'd do what he says.
你很大方,少校.
Your offer is very generous, Major.
没错.
Yes, it is.
但是, McKay 刚告诉我
However, Dr. McKay recently shared with me
你们有个拯救城市的计划.
there's a plan in action to save the city.
是么?
He did?
是的.
He did.
我知道还有最后一个地下站
My understanding is there is
one final grounding station
需要被停止.
that needs to be deactivated.
将3号站的避雷针拿走,
Uncouple the grounding rods at station three,
这样可以让防御系统重新运作
assist with the reactivation of the shield
那么你和你的朋友可以安全的离开这里.
and you and your friends can leave here, unharmed.
等等e.
Wait a minute.
我以为你要的是C-4和飞船.
I thought all you wanted was C-4 and a Jumper.
为什么不在你可以的时候控制这座城市呢,少校?
Why raid a city when you can seize it, Major?
Atlantis 要不就是我们的,要不就沉入大海...
Atlantis will be ours or the ocean's...
你选吧.
You choose.
少校还没有消息么.
We should have heard something from the major by now.
或许他已经没有计划了.
Perhaps he has not had the opportunity.
我不想知道这里发生的一切.
I don't like not knowing what's going on in there.
Genii为什么会袭击我们?
Why would the Genii attack us?
为什么是现在?
Why now?
我们没有及时的离开.
We didn't exactly leave on the best terms.
我的意思是,除了我们偷了他们的一些装置
I mean, beside from the fact that
we stole some of their gear
没有把我们承诺过的C-4给他们,
and didn't hand over the C-4 we promised them,
他们认定Teyla干掉了两个他们最棒的家伙.
they're pretty convinced Teyla killed
one of their top guys.
他们错得真离谱.
They believe so falsely.
他们选择在我们最弱的时候偷袭我们一定不是巧合.
The fact that they chose our weakest hour
cannot be a coincidence.
一定有人告诉了他们我们现在很弱.
Someone must have told them that
we would be at a diminished capacity.
一定会有其他办法的.
There's got to be a way back.
外面的风速有110里/时.
Those winds outside are blowing at 110 knots.
我们哪里也去不了.
We're not going anywhere, son.
谢谢你来看我.
Thank you for seeing me.
这座城市是我们祖先设计居住并留给他们的后代的,
This city was designed to be inhabited by the Ancients
and their direct descendants, and although, yes,
但是对于不是他们后代的人来说,他们无法运用这个城市的大部分功能,
while there is limited functionality
for those who do not posses the ancient gene,
只有他们的后代才能操控整座城市.
it's only those who have it
who can revive this city to its true potential.
你是么?
And you have this gene?
不,但是我们的人里面很多都是.
No, but many of my team do.
幽灵正慢慢袭来.
The Wraith are slowly waking.
很快整个星系都将被卷入一场浩劫,我们谁都不愿意看到.
Soon this entire galaxy will be embroiled in a war
the likes of which our generations have never seen.
你加速了这场战争.
A war that you expedited.
和我们不同的意见没什么用.
Disagreements like ours will no longer matter.
我们唯一需要知道的就是如何备战,
The only thing of any consequence
will be how prepared we are,
如何防御.
and what defense we are able to mount.
现在,这座城市里有很多秘密可以帮助我们打赢这场战争...
Now, this city holds many secrets
which could help us win that war...
但是只有在我的人发现这些秘密的情况下.
But only if my team are here to discover them.
所以,拿走你想要的东西吧,如果你不将这座城市留下,
So fine, take whatever you need for your people,
but if you don't leave us this city,
你只是将自己送上死路.
you're only hurting yourselves in the long run.
你相信你的那些人,可是他们之中很多甚至不是这个星系的人,
You believe your people,
who are not even of this galaxy,
难道他们会比我们更接近ancients?
are closer to the ancients than we are?
你 傲慢的态度真是太过分了.
Your arrogance is astounding.
我们会掌控这座城市,我们会展开防卫,
We will take this city, we will mount a defense,
而且我们会赢,不需要你们的帮助,Weir博士.
and we will win, with or without your help, Dr. Weir.
长官,他现在在地下站.
Sir, he's at the grounding station.
在这里.
The commander is here.
他就站在这里,长官.
He's just standing there, sir.
待着别动.
Hold your position.
在他完成之前别接近他.
Do not approach until he's finished.
遵命,长官.
Yes, sir.
除非必要,不要开枪.
Use lethal force only if necessary.
你说过不会伤害他的.
You told him he would be unharmed.
希望他别做太多反抗.
Let's hope he doesn't put up much of a fight.
他停下了,他现在不在控制台周围了.
He's stopped.
He's not at the control panel anymore.
他正四处看.
He's looking around.
准备开火.
Hold your fire.
那些控制板很容易被破坏的.
Those control panels are pretty fragile.
你不会希望...
You might not want to...
让我来告诉你,你都做错了些什么, Kolya.
Let me tell you what you did wrong here, Kolya.
a), 你失去了2个你的人...
a), you lost two of your men...
b)...
在我把避雷装置停止之前你把开关毁了...
You've damaged the switch before
I could separate the grounding rods...
我相信McKay会对此很吃惊...
Which I'm sure you're gonna
get an earful from McKay for...
还有, c)...
And, c)...
你毁了我对你最后的信任.
You lost all of what little
credibility you had with me.
你明白这意味着什么么?
Do you have any idea how big a setback that is?
我再也无法启动防御系统.
I may not even be able to activate the shield.
我不可能... 离开我!
I can't possibly... Get off me!
你干掉了2个我的人.
You killed two of my men.
我想我们也会.
I guess we're even.
我不喜欢你.
I don't like you.
我还没说完.
I'm not finished yet.
我也没有.
Neither am I.
跟Weir博士告别吧.
Say goodbye to Dr. Weir.
这个城市有个自毁开关.
This city has a self destruct button.
如果你碰了她,我就启动.
You hurt her, I'll activate it.
没人会得到Atlantis.
Nobody'll get Atlantis.
就算如此, 少校,你也需要两个高级人员来启动它...
Even if it exists, Major, you need at least
two senior personnel to activate it...
而我现在准备送一个人上路.
And I'm about to take one of them out of the equation.
Kolya!
我给你一条船!
I'll give you a ship!
我会离开!
I'll fly it out of here for you myself!
Kolya!